Drag and drop inside the main 3D window the 2 surfaces: the Outer Enamel Surface (OES) and Enamel Dentine Junction (EDJ)
Camera mode: "CTRL + middle click drag" to translate selected surfaces
Initial position can be reset by pressing "Undo" (CTRL+Z)
Let's hide the grid
Scalars=> compute thickness between two surfaces
It's important here to invert the normals of the observed object (the EDJ).
Thickness computation takes a little while...
Let's wait...
Be patient...
Almost done ?
wait...
Ready?????
Here we are!
Open the edit scalars window.
Use suggested min and suggested max values as display range boundaries
Let's play with the shift range slider
Color scale (colors and transparency levels) can be adjusted interactively.