Tutorial 15: learn how to prepare a 3D model to be printed on a Prusa i3 MK3s printer. Open a web browser and go to https://doi.org/10.1111/pala.12429
The article "Apparatus architecture of the conodont Nicoraella kockeli (Gondolelloidea, Prioniodinina) constrains functional interpretations" contains supplementary data
Click on https://doi.org/10.5523/bris.p515kyhwv3ec29zo7an2psqju
This opens the 3D model supplementary data webpage
You can download the .PLY file an unzip it
It takes a little bit longer than expected... sorry for the delay
A few seconds left...
Now open the .PLY file with MorphoDig
You can activate the "RGB" array to display the colors.
Many 3D software, and most 3D printer software expect surface models to be expressed in millimeters ("mm").
Default grid size in MorphoDig is set up so that 1 square is 1cm * 1cm long. Meanwhile this conodont 3D model is expected to be less than 1mm long in its largest dimension.
We can deduce that this model is probably expressed in "nanometers" (because the original specimen was scanned at a nanometric resolution). We can select this model and reduce its size by a factor of 1000 to express it in "mm".
Do do so, replace the first three "1" of the diagonal of the position matrix by 0.001
Click on apply to all selected surfaces
We see here that the model is now now much smaller, around  1 mm long, which is what we expect it to be.
We may rename this object to remind us that we reexpressed it using mm units.
Now let's click on "harden transform" to apply this matrix to the model.
We can re-orient the 3D model so that it gets a more convenient orientation during the 3D printing process.
You can use the yellow sliders to change the 3D model orientation
Here "CTRL" + middle click is used to translate the model.
Rotation yellow slider...
Then again "CTRL" + middle click (translation) and then "CTRL" +  left click (rotation)
Rotation yellow slider again
"CTRL" + middle click (translation)
Now let's harden transform once again the position matrix.
We can change the name of the model to remind us that its position was changed
We do not want (nor can) print a 1mm long object. We have to increase the size of the 3D model. Let's choose a rescaling factor.
A multiplication factor of 200 seems quit good to produce a fairly big enough 3D model of this conodont.
Again, let's harden this transformation matrix.
1 square of the grid is 1cm*1cm, so now, this 3D model is around 11 cm tall and slightly less than 20 cm long, which will nicely fit on a Prusa i3 MK3 printer bed.
Again, we can modify the name of the 3D model to remind us that we will print a 3D model that has been increased 200 times (so not a "real size" conodont!).
Let's save the project (in order not to lose all the repositioning and rescaling)
We can create a new folder
If we printed this 3D model directly, the different conodont ellements would fall apart, because they lack connectivity. And we would lose the orientation and position of all these elements.
In order keep all the conodont elements in their current orientations and positions, we need to produce so-called "connective struts". This can be achieved in MorphoDig inside the menue "Create 3D primitives".
Here for instance, we create a 13 cm long * 6 cm large * 6mm tall  rectangular shape that will be the "base" of our 3D print
Let's reposition this rectangular parallelepiped object
"CTRL" + middle click to translate it
Let's view it from front side
"CTRL" + middle click again
Now let us "glue together" a few conodont elements.
Let's start to create a few cylinders (10 for instance). For this model to be correctly 3D printed, we will need between 30 and 40 connective struts.
The most time consuming task is now to give a good position and orientation in space to each cylinder in order to "stick together" all conodont element.
"CTRL" + middle click to translate this cylinder. "CTRL" + left click to change its orientation....
2 elements are  becoming connected in 3D space.
We can now proceed with a second cylinder. Do not forget to save your project from time to time ("CTRL +A" to select all objects, and then "CTRL + S" so save the project).
[...] Less than 1 hour later  : all conodont elements are now connected with around 40 cylinders correctly positionned !
This 3D model is ready for 3D printing! Do not forget to save your project  ("CTRL +A" to select all objects, and then "CTRL + S" so save the project).
Select all 3D objects ("CTRL" + A), and save as a single STL file.
Press "Save"
RGB information will be lost in this STL file. But this is ok to print a single color model.
Choose Position => modified. This is very important : the position matrix of each connective strut (cylinders and rectangular shapes) will be hardened transformed inside the 3D single STL file.
Now let's swich to the 3D printer software. In our case, we will print this model with a Prusa i3 MK3S, and use PrusaSlicer software
Import the previously created 3D STL file.
The 3D model fits nicely on the 3D printer bed.
The most important parameter in PrusaSlicer is that we need to build support everywhere. We chose a printing layer height of 0.2 mm, which is a good compromise between printing time and printing quality for a 20cm long model.
Let's slice the 3D model
This is how this model will look once 3D printed. All the 3D support material will have to be removed by hand.
Here we can preview how the printed object will look after we will have removed all support material.
Let's export the G-code and print it!
The Prusa i3 MK3S has started a few minutes ago.
Around 20 hours later...
Once the 3D support material has been removed (by hand, mostly using pliers), it looks pretty good! A 3D conodont apparatus printed at a scale of 200.