Open the "Primate_femur_thickness" project (NTW)
2 surface bones are opened. A right femur of Erythrocebus pattas (smaller) and a right femur of Papio sp. (larger)
Select the right femur of Erythrocebus patas (right click+ drag)
Scalars=> compute thickness within each selected surface. For this femur, we do not expect cortical thickness to exceed 3mm.
(set this value as low as possible to decrease computation time)
Here, I pressed cancel because thickness computation time is quite too long for this video!
For the papio femur, we do not expect cortical thickness to exceed 9 mm (set this value as low as possible to decrease computation time)
Again I pressed cancel because thickness computation time is relatively long
Now activate "Thickness" scalar
Open scalars window
Set display range using "suggested min" and "suggested max" values.
You can shift display range as desired
In order to compare bone thickness distribution patterns in Erythrocebus and Papio, let's normalize bone thickness' scalar
Thickness scalar can also be normalized for the right femur of Papio
Now let's activate "Norm_thickness" scalar. Now we can compare bone thickness distribution patterns in those 2 bones of different size.
Let's activate the tags array.
Open the "Tag" window
Import the correct tag map!
3 bone regions have been tagged (the 2 epiphyses, and the shaft)
Now you can save information regarding the perviously computed scalar arrays (Thickness , Norm_Thickness etc.)
for each bone region defined in the tags