Drag and drop the inner ear surface file
In "move selected objects" mode, selected objects can be: 1) translated (middle click + drag)
2) rotated (left click + drag)
This surface already contains a "RGB" array. Let's render those RGB colors.
Activate "Flag digitization" mode
"L" + left click to digitize a new flag
All newly digitized flags have the same color and length
Let's select one flag (that placed on the common crus) and rotate it (CTRL + left click drag)
To "redigitize" a given flag, press "L" + right click.
Here, we have selected all the flags and change their size
Here, we have selected all the flags and are about to change their color to that of the structure they are placed on
Now let's change flag captions : open the edit first select flag window