Drag and drop the RAW file inside the main 3D window
The Open RAW Volume windows shows up
Fill  data type (8 bits, 16bits, 32 bits...), data dimensions (number of voxels in x, y and z dimensions),
header size (if greater than 0)
Requested size should be equal to file size
Fill data endianess (when Data Type is 16bits or 32 bits). For 8 bits dataset, endianess does not matter.
µCT Images  are most often "Back to Front" ordered, but here we have a "Front to back" RAW volume.
Then fill voxel size : in this example,  36µm = 0.036mm
This RAW volume contains more than 500*500*500 voxels, and a warning message shows up.
Large dataset are difficult to render on the graphics card (the computer may crash).
By default, MorphoDig will render a subsampled version of  a given dataset when the number
of voxels exceeds 500*500*500 voxels.
Open the "Edit first selected volume window"
(selected volumes have a bounding box outline... WARNING: only selected volumes can be interacted with)
Here we can test whether our graphics card can render the full dataset (594*294*1038 voxels)
Apparently it can without trouble.
Then we can increase manually this "out of core" threshold value (Edit=> Edit volume options)
Let's set this value to 200 million voxels. Next time we will open this RAW volume, the warning message will not show up.
Now let's change the display values
The shift slider moves the display min and max values together.
You may also adjust the max value alone with the max slider.
Same thing for the min value
Transparency levels can be adjusted interactively.
The colormap can be also changed using the "colormaps" combo box.