Open surface file. 3 possibilities. 1) Click on open data
2) File=>Surface => open surface  3) drag and drop surface file inside 3D window
The 3D surface appears in grey : it is selected and can be rotated / translated
Click on the "yellow arrow" button to activate "Move selected objects" mode
Left click + drag mouse to rotate the surface
Middle click + drag mouse to translate the surface
By default, 1 square = 1cm * 1cm.
Grid size can be changed. Here 1 square will be 1mm*1mm
Mouse roll to zoom-in or zoom out
3D surfaces can be rotated / translated using the yellow sliders on the side of the screen
The surface is now positionned in a "biologically relevant" orientation
Use the 6 camera predefined orientations to view your model from all sides (which is useful when digitizing landmarks)
Activate "camera mode" to rotate the camera (left click + drag mouse)
Hide/display grid
Right click + drag mouse draws a rectangle ( select/unselect objects ). When drawn "yellow", the surface is unselected.
Open the "edit first selected object window"
The position matrix differs from the identity matrix. You can save this position matrix
Surface positions can be saved inside .POS files
In order to avoid to select/unselect surfaces with right click + drag mouse, it is advisable to activate "landmark mode" when digitizing landmarks
Maintain "L" key pressed + left mouse click to create new landmarks
Landmark rendering size can be adjusted
When landmark mode is activated, only landmark objects can be selected/unselected
Most actions can be undone (such as "landmark digitization")
"L" + right click: if a single landmark is selected, its position will be updated
Selected landmarks can be reordered (increased or decreased in landmark list)
To access internal structures, enable ROI (region of interest), and click on "Display ROI"
Now use the "control points" (spheres) to adjust the dimensions of the ROI (region of interests)
Regions outside the ROI box become invisible.
Hide ROI box in order to digitize landmarks inside the cranium
Press CTRL+D to unselect all opened objects at once
To digitize  landmarsk at the center of foramina, first place them at the border of the structure
In a second step, move them one by one.
1) Select landmark (right mouse click & drag)
2) CTRL + mouse middle click & drag (landmark digitization mode activated)
To save a project, press CTRL+A (select all opened objects) then click on the "save project" button
Press "Delete" if you want to delete all selected objects
You may reopen the project