Drag and drop project file (.NTW) inside main 3D window
When opening a NTW file, 3D volumes and 3D surfaces will be unselected by default.
To interact with the opened volume, it must be selected first (right click + drag). Selected volumes are drawn with a bounding box.
Use the yellow sliders to rotate/translate selected volumes
Activate "move selected objects" interaction mode
Now use "left click + drag" to rotate the volume, and "middle click + drag" to translate the volume
Active "move camera mode"
Open the "edit first selected volume" window
Click on "display Crop box" button.
Adjust the bounds of the crop box (left click + drag the spherical controls)
Now click on "crop". As the volume was rotated, a warning message shows up, indicating that the volume data will be resliced before being cropped
Thats it ! Notice that a post fix ( "_rsp_crp") is added to the name of the volume, to remind us that it was resliced and cropped.
Now browse through the re-oriented 2D slices.
Modified volume data can be saved inside a new MetaImage (MHD/MHA) file
The metaimage (MHD/MHA) format is convenient: it can be used in a wide range of other software, including FIJI
Here we compare with FIJI the initial metaimage volume, and the resliced + cropped final volume data.