Drag and drop inner ear surface file inside the main 3D window
Activate "move selected objects" mode
In this mode, objects can be translated (middle click + drag) or rotated (left click + drag).
Positionning inner ears in a "biologically relevant" orientation will make it easier to digitize curves.
Tutorial data contain a position file ".POS" which you can directly drag and drop in the main 3D window to position the selected inner ear surface
You may decide to hide the grid
Curve digitization inside inner ear canals is much easier on "transparent" surfaces
VERY IMPORTANT: activate "Digitize curve node landmarks" button
Press "L" + left click to digitize new curve node landmarks
Let's draw rough outlines along the three semi-circular canals as well.
You may change the background color to increase the visibility of the inner structures and of the curve node outlines
Let's finish to digitize a rough outline for the posterior semi-circular canal
As  we will have to move A LOT the position of curve nodes and curve handles, so it's better to activate "Landmark Digitization mode",
which will prevent to select/unselect the 3D surface while doing these adjustments
Here, we select the 3 node landmarks placed at the beginning of the lateral, anterior and posterior canals,
(11, 17 and 23) and define them as "Curve starting nodes"
Now the rough cochlear outline and those of the 3 semi-circular canals are separated in space
Now let's position each curve node landmark inside the cochlea/canals
To do that select 1 single node landmark, and (in landmark digitization mode) press CTRL + middle click drag
Select 2nd curve node, then press CTRL + middle click drag to move it
Select 3rd curve node, then press CTRL + middle click drag to move it
Select next curve node, then press CTRL + middle click drag to move it etc.
Proceed (select next curve node, then press CTRL + middle click drag to move it)
until all curve node landmarks are located at the center of the cochlea / semi-circular canals
Oncel all curve node landmarks are located at the center of the cochlea / semi-circular canals, save
them inside a .VER file (File => Curves => Save curve node landmarks)
Now go in File=>Curves=>Load Curve Handle landmarks and choose the file you just have saved.
A expected, a series of curve handle landmarks have been created, and each curve handle has
the same position as its node counterpart
Now select all handle landmarsk (it does not matter if node landmarks are selected as well) and open the
"Move curve handles semi-automatically" menu
All curve handles have been moved , but have not yet reached an optimal position.
The last (and most time consuming) step is to adjust manually the position of each curve node and each curve handle to
follow the center of each semi-circular canal and of the cochlea (Select one single landmark, then press CTRL + middle click drag)