Open "initial_position" project file (.NTW), this will open all the bones in their original orientation and position in space
All 3D surfaces are now opened
Mouse roll middle button to zoom-in or zoom-out
You may decide to hide the grid
Let's change lighting options
Open the "edit first selected surface" window
Click on the arrows to browse through all opened surfaces
Right click + drag mouse to select manually one or several surface objects at once
In "Move selected objects  mode", CTRL + mouse middle button drag translates the camera
Now in "Camera mode", CTRL + mouse middle button drage will translate selected objects
Use also the yellow sliders to rotate / translate selected objects
CTRL + middle click drag to translate the left mandible
Yellow slider to rotate left mandible along the z viewing axis
Yellow slider to rotate left mandible along the y viewing axis
CTRL + middle click drag to translate the mandible
Several vertebrae are now selected at once
CTRL + middle click drag to translate all selected vertebrae at once
Select the 2 remaining caudal vertebrae and translate them as well (CTRL + middle click drag)
In "Move selected objects" mode, no need to press "CTRL", Left mouse button drag is enough to rotate selected objects
Now let's select every objects (alternative: CTRL+A), and delete them (DEL button)
Now open the "anatomical_position" project (NTW file)
Now all bones are given a "biologically relevant" orientation and position.
Let's browse through the  vertebrae
Select the cranium and mandibles
Translate the cranium and mandibles ("Move selected obejcts" mode, then middle click drag)
This last action can be undone (click on undone or "CTRL + Z")