Drag and drop all TIFF files inside the main 3D window
Fill voxel size (here: 36µm = 0.036mm). And choose between "front to back" or "back to front" image order.
Here, image order is "back to front".
You may choose to hide the grid
Open the "edit first selected volume" window
(selected volumes have a bounding box outline)
You may decide to hide the volume rendering representation
and to display instead XY, XZ, or YZ slices.
Lighting options can be adjusted in order to enhance the visibility of structures.
Display range can be shifted in order to visualize dense inner structures such as the bones
Volume data can be exported in the MetaImage format (MHD or MHA)
When saved as MHD, two files will be created: a .mhd (header) file, and a .raw/.zraw (data) file
Data can be compressed
Header (.mhd) file contain relevant information such as data type, data dimension and voxel size
Metaimage files (MHD/MHA) can be read and written with Fiji, and with many other software.