Drag and drop the "MHD" (Meta-Image) file inside the main 3D window
Lighting settings can be adjusted in order to see better the 3D structures
Most µCT data are not oriented in a "biologically relevant" manner.
In "Camera mode", selected volumes (drawn with a box outline) can be:
1) rotated (CTRL + left mouse drag)
2) translated (CTRL + middle mouse drag)
The yellow sliders can also be useful to translate / rotate selected volumes
The tutorial data folder also contains a "POS" (position) file which you can drag and drop inside the 3D main window.
Notice that the volume is now unselected (no bounding box outline drawn)
(to select/unselect volumes:  right mouse drag)
Let's digitize a few landmarks ("L" + left mouse click)
Let's adjust slightly the display range (slider "shift" of the Edit first selected volume window)
Now let's digitize landmarks inside the mouse's cranium. To do so, we need to enable ROI, and display ROI
Move the spherical controls (left click + drag) to adjust the bounds of the ROI box
Now the "Edit first selected volume" window can be closed
Now simply digitize landmarks inside the cranium ("L" + left click).
Remember : landmark digitization actions can be undone (CTRL +Z) and redone (CTRL +Y). Also to change the position of a given landmark , select it and press "L" + right click
Now we can save all digitized landmarks inside a text file
The first 3 numbers are the x y z coordinates of each landmark, and the last 3 numbers contain the x y z orientation of the normale.