Drag and drop Inner ear surface file inside the main 3D window
"Move selected objects mode": Left click drag to rotate the selected surface
Middle click drag to translate the selected surface
Yellow sliders can be used as well to translate / rotate selected objects
Create a new tag array
Now open the tag window
Tag region name and color can be edited
Select lasso tag tool
Draw a contour around the cochlea
Let's edit corresponding tag region color
Let's use again the lasso to tag the lateral canal
The wrong active tag region was selected (Cochlea instead of lateral canal)
Let's reuse the lasso to tag the lateral canal
Pencil: press "T" + left click
Pencil size can be adjusted interactively by pressing "T" + roll mouse
Let's tag the anterior canal now
Let's use the lasso
Now the posterior canal
Let's use the lasso first
Again the lasso
Some regions of the lateral canal should be completed
Let's use again the pencil ("T" + left click)
Lateral canal ampulla
Tag region transparency can be also adjusted as desired
Let's tag the common crus
The wrong tag region is active
Instead of retagging the common crus, we can simply "Undo" last action (CTRL + Z)
Let's use the paint bucket tool with "tag propagation" option activated to tag the vestibulum
"T" + left click was pressed and unfortunately, all other regions were overriden (let's undo that!)
=> Instead, we should press "T" + right click to avoid region override.
Let's use the pencil now to complete the task